live. Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the ten
commandments that God commanded for the
whole world to keep. Brother James,
and God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which had brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shalt have no
other gods before me. Thou shall not
make unto thee any grave in image, or
any likeness of anything that is in
heaven above, or that is in the earth
beneath, or that is in the water under
the earth. Thou shalt not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I,
the Lord thy God, am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers,
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy. Sixth day shalt thou labor
and do all thy work, but the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou shalt not do any work. Thou nor
thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man's
servant, nor thy maidervant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in them is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hollowed it. Honor thy father
and thy mother, that thy days may be
long upon the land which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shalt not kill.
Thou shalt not commit adultery. Thou
shalt not steal. Thou shalt not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shalt not covet thy neighbor's house.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's
wife, nor as man's servant, nor as maid
servant, nor as ox, nor as ass, nor
anything that is thy neighbors.
>> I read Exodus 20:es 1-17.
May the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of this word. In Jesus name we
pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the long scripture
questions as well as the vague questions
and questions of debate. We are not here
to debate. We are here to spread the
true gospel of Jesus. So, please be as
direct as possible with your questions
so we can be as direct as possible with
our answers out of the King James Bible.
No other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind that this is a live stream, so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We're just
asking that you please keep them to a
two scripture maximum. But let me
introduce to you the family on the panel
this evening. We got brother Dre. Good
evening,
>> brother Jerome.
>> Rest in peace,
>> Brother Julius.
>> All right, we read your lips. Brother
James,
>> good evening everyone.
>> Sister Deborah,
>> good evening.
>> Brother Sean,
>> Brother Julius,
>> good evening everybody.
>> And we have the guest caller with us.
And I'm brother Cornell. What is our
first question of the evening?
>> Uh yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Ata Masala asked you to explain First
Timothy 5 verse9.
>> All right. First Timothy 5 and verse 9.
Would like a little light on it. Brother
Jerome,
>> let's go read it.
>> Brother James, if you can, can you read
verse uh 9 and 10 for me?
>> Sure. 1 Timothy 5:9 and 10 says, "Let
not a widow be taken into the number
under three score years old, having been
the wife of one man,
well reported of for good works, if she
have brought up children, if she have
loded strangers, if she has washed the
saints feet, if she have relieved the
afflicted, if she have diligently
followed every good work,
Okay. What that's talking about is let
not the widow that's 60 years old
that's doing uh verse 10 which we just
read be numbered with the
younger widows that's doing verse 11
through13.
Let's read verse 11 through13.
>> Okay.
>> Go ahead. But the younger widows refuse.
For when they have begun to wax wanting
against Christ, they will marry, having
damnation, because they have cast off
their first faith. And with all they
learn to be idol, wandering about from
house to house, and not only idle, but
tattlers also in busy bodies, speaking
things which they ought not.
So let not the older widows
60 years old that's doing the things
that's pleasing the Lord be number with
the younger widows that's not doing the
things that's pleasing to the Lord.
That's all I got on.
>> All right. Thank you for that brother.
Hope that answered that question. Next
question.
>> Next one. Mel and Natural Journey asks,
"What is the difference between being
religious and being spiritual?"
>> All right. Being religious and being
spiritual. What is the difference
between the two, brother Julius?
>> Uh there's close similarities. Good
evening, everybody. close similarities,
but uh religion is a physical thing, a
physical practice, and religion is more
mental. I'm going to show you what I'm
talking about. Let's go to James the
first chapter. [clears throat]
James the first chapter,
being charitable, uh the actions, your
faith, and what you do because of your
faith.
James 1, pick it up at verse 22.
James 1, verse 22. Pure religion. Watch
this right here. Go ahead.
>> But be ye doers of the word and not
hearers only.
>> Deceiving your own selves.
>> Be ye doers of the word and not hearers
only. Deceiving yourselves. Skip down to
verse 26. 26 and 27. Go ahead.
If any man among you seem to be
religious, and bridleth not his tongue,
>> but deceiveth his own heart, this man's
religion is vain.
>> Because you say something, but don't do
nothing about it. You say, "Well, I'm
religious." Well, you could say that,
but then what is pure religion? Read the
next verse.
>> Pure religion and undefiled before God
and the father is this. Uhhuh.
>> To visit the fatherless and
>> widow. That's the word. That's that's
action. That's that's putting your faith
into works. Go ahead.
>> To visit the fatherless and widows in
their affliction.
>> And to keep himself unspotted from the
world.
>> Those are your physical behaviors.
You're religious.
So you're going to do the things that
God say do. Love one another. the
charities that you do toward uh the the
elders and the people and the of the
church, your neighbor. But then the
other part of that is being spiritual.
That's a more mental thing. Start with
your mental thinking, your faith, your
prayer. Let's go to 1 Corinthians
chapter 2.
1 Corinthians James chapter 2
and we're going to read 12-15.
1 Corinthians. Now, here the spiritual
things. 1 Corinthians
2 and start reading at verse 12. Go
ahead, my brother.
>> Now, we have received not the spirit of
the world, but the spirit which is of
God.
>> Uhhuh.
>> That we might know the things that are
freely given to us of God.
which which things also we speak, not in
the words which man's wisdom teacheth.
>> Uhhuh.
>> But which the Holy Ghost teacheth.
>> Yes.
>> Comparing spiritual things with
spiritual.
>> These are mental things, things in your
mind, things that spoken to you and how
you carry them out. But go ahead. But
you got to receive them first. You got
to have wisdom, knowledge, and
understand. These things are spiritual.
Continue.
But the natural man receiveth not the
things of the spirit of God.
>> Uhhuh.
>> For they are foolishness unto him.
>> Neither can he know them because they
are spiritually discerned.
>> Go ahead.
>> But he that is spiritual judgeth all
things.
>> Yeah.
>> Yet he himself is judged of no man.
>> Because he's walking in the law. Who can
blame you if you walking in the law? So
the difference between being religious
is your actions and being spiritual
starts with your your thoughts, your
meditations, your prayer, your prayer.
It starts here first sisters and
brothers with the word of God and then
it carries out into your behaviors. So
that's the difference. One is mental,
one is spiritual.
One one is a action and one is uh
mental.
>> That's the best I could do with that.
>> Yes sir.
We also know, brother Julius, faith
without works is dead, brother.
>> And that's why the book said, "Be ye
don't be just hearers of the words, but
doers."
>> That's right.
>> Faith without works is dead. You need
them both, but you have to put them in
their proper context.
>> That is correct. All right. Thank you
for that, brother. Hope that answered
that question as we move on to our next
one.
>> Next one. be alert as did all the tribe
of Levi split from the northern tribes.
>> Okay. When it came to the split, did all
the tribes of Levi split from the
northern tribes? Brother Jerome.
>> Uh yes, it did. Um let's go read about
it. Um when when it kind of took place,
let's go to uh 2 Coronicles.
2 Coronicles chapter 13.
and we're going to read verse four and
then we going to skip
you. Go ahead and read.
>> Okay. And Abjah stood upon Mount
Zamarim, which is in Mount Ephraim, and
said, "Hear me, thou Jeroboam, and all
Israel." So at this time, Jerem was over
the the northern tribes
as you stated in your question cuz it
had already been split uh split. Okay.
Uh read verse 9-10.
Have ye not cast out the priests of the
Lord, the sons of Aaron, and the
Levites, and have made you priests after
the manner of the nations of other
lands, so that whosoever cometh to
consecrate himself with a young bullock
and seven brs, the same may be a priest
of them that are no gods. Mhm.
>> But as for us, the Lord is our God, and
we have not forsaken him, and the priest
which minister unto the Lord are the
sons of Aaron, and the Levites wait upon
their business.
>> Skip down verse 12.
And behold, God himself is with us for
our captive and his priests with
sounding trumpets to cry alarm against
you,
>> oh children of Israel.
>> Fight ye not against the Lord God of
your fathers, for ye shall not prosper.
>> Let's tie this with uh the 11th chapter
and read verse 12 through 14. That'll be
it.
Okay. 2 Chronicles 11 12-14 says, "And
in every several city he put shields and
spears and made them exceeding strong,
having Judah and Benjamin on his side.
And the priests and the Levites that
were in all Israel resorted to him out
of all their coast. Mhm.
>> For the Levites left their suburbs and
their possessions, and came to Judah and
Jerusalem, for Jeroboam and his sons had
cast him off from executing the priest's
office unto the Lord.
>> That's all I got on you.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
As we move on to our next question,
>> next question. Kenya Haynes says,
"Elohim is the whole God's family from
my understanding.
Can you please explain Jesus and the
father first, then those who come
later?"
>> All right, guest caller, can you shed
some light on that question?
>> Yes. Uhhuh. Well, first thing is like I
said, Elohim that's a unipural word
which one family been that and more than
one member. It's just like man m a n
>> that's a unipur word one family but more
than one members. So in Elohim
the uh God which would would which would
be better defined as the godhead
it was just two in the beginning. St.
John first chapter read verses 1 and
two.
John verses 1 and two says, "In the
beginning was the word and the word was
with God and the word was God.
The same was in the beginning with God."
>> Now those that were just two, the one
that became the father and one that
became the son. In fact, they are still
the only ones that are part that I would
call a part of the God. head. But there
is another God out there, but he's not a
God of the Godhead, even though he's
God. Why? Because he was created. And
these guys, the uh Jesus and the Father
was not created. They existed. That's
why they both use the word uh the I am.
Now, but you got one that's a part of
the God family, but not a part of the
Godhead because he was created. Let's go
look at it. Let's go into Hebrews 11
chapter and read verse 5.
>> Okay. Hebrews 11 and verse 5 says, "By
faith Enoch was translated that he
should not see death and was not found
because God had translated him. For
before his translation, he had this
testimony that he pleased God."
>> Enoch pleased God. And God didn't see no
reason to to let him continue on in the
flesh and die. So translation mean
change from one thing to another. And
let's go back to Genesis the 5th chapter
and we going to read verses 21- 24.
Genesis 5 21- 24 says, "And Enoch lived
60 and5 years and begat Methuselah.
And Enoch walked with God after he begat
Methuselah 300 years and begott sons and
daughters.
And all the days of Enoch were 360
and5 years. And Enoch walked with God
and he was not for God took him.
>> So now people you that will see God took
him to heaven. No, he just took him from
among men because he was changed. Once
he was changed, then he was just like
the uh third of the angels that had that
the Lord had thrown out of heaven. They
are spirit beings, but they are in the
chains of darkness. So when he when when
Enoch was changed, you couldn't have a,
you know, you couldn't have a guy
walking around in uh uh uh
on this earth, God among men in his
strength because he look like a
flashlight cuz cuz God is uh uh when it
when define God when you change, you
start to take on a shine. So Enoch is
God, but he ain't a part of Godhead
because he was created. But he's saying
he was not because he was taken. People
said think that he was taken to heaven.
But then the word of Jesus uh uh uh
contradicts that. Let's go into St. John
the 3 chapter
and read verse 13.
>> Okay. John 3:13 says, "And no man hath
ascended up to heaven, but he that came
down from heaven, even the son of man
which is in heaven."
So now, he not was a man before he was
God. So he was not taken to heaven.
Jesus said, "No man is going to heaven
but but the son of man speaking of
himself." So now, where is he not? He's
running around this earth under chains
of darkness just like those angels
are. But as far as and uh uh what him
being changed shouldn't be no great big
mystery.
So the Lord can do in the beginning what
he's going to do in the end.
>> Yes sir.
>> But the end is he come cuz Enoch never
died but Jesus died. That mean that
Jesus was the firstborn from the dead.
firstborn from the dead. Now, let's go
and show you at what time that's going
to happen. Let's go to 1 Corinthians
15th chapter and first we're going to
read verses 21 to 25.
>> Okay,
>> 23. 21 to 23.
>> Okay, that is 1 Corinthians 15 21-23.
They say, "For since by man came death,
by man came also the resurrection of the
dead.
For as in Adam all die, even so in
Christ shall all be made alive."
>> But but every man in his own order,
Christ the first fruits, afterward they
that are Christ at his coming.
See now in Adam we die but in Jesus we
going to be made alive
when
at his coming because he's the first
fruit. He's the first fruit born from
the dead. Enoch never died.
>> So now
but Enoch was changed. Why is because
God man was created to become God. Now
let's see what's going to happen to the
rest of them. Let's skip down and read.
We're going to read from verse 49 53.
>> Okay. Verse 49 says, "And as we have
borne the image of the earthy, we shall
also bear the image of the heavenly.
Now this I Now this I say, brethren,
that flesh and blood cannot inherit the
kingdom of God, neither do corruption
inherit incorruption.
Behold, I show you a mystery. We shall
not all sleep, but we shall all be
changed.
In a moment, in the twinkling of an eye,
at the last trump, for the trumpet shall
sound, and the dead shall be raised
incorruptible, and we shall be changed.
For this,
>> what it's telling you,
>> what it's telling you here that we not
all going to die, but everybody is going
to be changed. The only difference is
the people that's going to be changed at
Jesus coming and Enoch is that Enoch was
changed in the first day. The rest of us
going to be changed in the last day and
just before the last day because God
created us to live forever. Keep reading
to 53.
For this corruptible must put on
incorruption and this mortal must put on
immortality.
So that's what's got to happen. Enoch is
immortal right now
because God created man. He didn't say
we shall not all He didn't say just a
handful is going to change. He said we
shall not all sleep but we shall all be
changed.
Enoch has made the change. And Enoch is
God. How do I know he's God? Let's go
into uh Psalm chapter 82.
And we're going to read verses 1 and 2,
6 and 7.
>> Okay.
Psalm 82
1 and 2 says, "God standeth in the
congregation of the mighty. He judgeth
among the gods.
>> Now, who do you think he's talking to? A
but two in the God family.
>> As he judge among the mighty and he
judge among the gods as in plural, he's
talking to us.
>> But something happened.
Keep reading.
>> How long will ye judge unjustly and
accept the persons of the wicked?
>> Now, that's exactly what we did. Adam
and Eve did in the garden of Eden. So
what happened to this immortal talent?
Skip down to verse and read verse 6 and
7.
>> Verse six says, "I have said ye are gods
and all of you are children of the most
high, but ye shall die like men and fall
like one of the princes."
>> So now God called us God.
>> But what happened was we listen to the
wrong person. That mean we ate from the
wrong tree and God put a death sentence
on us. And that's what we're doing right
now. And this death sentence is going to
prevail until Jesus return and run this
earth for a thousand years and then had
a white throne judgment. Then not going
to be no more death sinners. But
everybody then will be God.
Everybody. Because Jesus told you and we
don't have to go read that in Matthew
10th chapter is that look he called them
gods to whom the word of God came. Man
was created to be God. So who created
him? The father and the son. And the
first one that became God was Enoch.
And at Jesus coming all the rest of us
will be a part of the God family. and we
all will come under the banner of
Elohim. That's all I got to say.
>> All right.
Hope that answers your question as we
continue to move on.
>> Moving on. Tomorrow Williams says,
"Those people who receive God's seal on
their forehead, will it be visible for
others to see?"
>> All right. So those people who receive
God's seal on their foreheads, will it
be visible for others to see? Just call
them.
>> I don't have a clue
cuz the Bible don't say it.
I can't read it.
>> All right, we're going to leave it right
there as we move on to our next
question.
>> Next question. Stephen Guggis asks, "Are
we only supposed to drink a kosher wine?
Is kosher biblical?"
>> All right. Kosha wine. Is that the only
wine that we should be drinking? And is
it biblical, Brother Drake?
>> No, it's not. And uh kosher wine is
something that Edom does and they take
their people to to uh make the wine
through the whole process. But I want to
show you something that Jesus did. Let's
go to uh John the 2 chapter. John the 2
chapter and we going to read verses 7-
11.
his his uh his mother wanted him to make
wine for this marriage
that that they were having. They was
running out of wine. His mother came and
asked him, pick it up at verse 7. What
did Jesus say?
Jesus said unto them, "Fill the water
pots with water." And they filled them
up to the brim.
And he said unto them, "Draw out now and
bear unto the governor of the feast."
And they bare it. When the ruler of the
feast had tasted the water that was made
wine, and knew not whence it was, but
the servants which drew the water knew.
The governor of the feast called the
bridegroom, and saith unto him, Every
man at the beginning doest set forth
good wine, and when men have well drunk,
then that which is worse, but thou has
kept the good wine until now.
The beginning of miracles did Jesus in
Canaa of Galilee and manifested forth
his glory and his disciples believed on
him.
>> So Jesus made wine from water. But the
this process that Edom is using, they
use only their people to uh go through
the fermenting, touching the grapes. And
you got to be a Sabbath observant uh uh
worshipper within there. But there's
nothing biblical that ties to that.
That's all I got.
>> All right. Yes, sir. Dre says, "That was
good wine."
>> That was good wine.
>> Yes, sir. All right. We're gonna move on
to our next question with a time check.
>> Yes. The time is 7:59.
JFlo asks, "Is there a certain prayer or
biblical verse I can read to make me
happy and protect me from sin for the
day?"
>> Well, we can't say whether there be a
particular verse that can make you
happy, but there is some things that
that you can definitely do. And um
here's some Bible advice here that we're
going to read. Let's go to John 14. John
the 14th chapter
because reading this John 14, hey,
always makes me happy. Any verses here
might make you happy, too. John 14.
And pick it up at that verse two,
brother. And we're going to do some
skipping.
Go right ahead.
In my father's house are many mansions.
If it were not so, I would have told
you. I go to prepare a place for you.
>> Boy, that makes me smile, James.
>> Yes, indeed.
>> All right, skip down to that verse six,
brother.
>> Jesus saith unto him, I am the way, the
truth, and the life. No man can cometh
unto the father but by me.
>> Yes. So when you find this God, you have
found the only one you need. Skip down
to verse 15.
>> If ye love me, keep my commandments.
>> And that will help you to fight off that
sin by keeping those commandments of
God. Because he said, "If you love me,
keep my commandments." Skip down to
verse 21 and let's see what happens when
you keep those commandments. Go ahead.
He that he he that hath my commandments
and keepeth them, he it is that loveth
me. And he that loveth me shall be loved
of my father, and I will love him, and
will manifest myself to him. All right,
those right there are some good verses
to make you happy when you got the
knowledge of God because you can find
verses from Genesis to Revelation, all
66 books, and you can go in there and
find something that can make you happy
and can teach you further how to fight
sin. But let's go into second Timothy 2.
Second Timothy 2. And we're going to
read one verse, brother,
because this will help you also to find
more of what you are looking for. Second
Timothy 2 and 15. Go ahead.
>> Study to show thyself approved unto God,
a workman that needeth not to be
ashamed, rightly dividing the word of
truth.
>> Yes. And when you are somewhere being
taught the true uncut pure word of God,
that is something worth smiling for
every time you hear it.
>> And Cordell, can I throw something in
there?
>> Go right ahead, brother.
>> Matthew 6. You can read it on your own.
Read the Lord's Prayer. It is loaded
with benefits.
>> Yeah. Yep. Indeed. Matthew the 6th
chapter. Yep. And you can read it from
that verse 9 all the way down. In fact,
stay tuned to the end of the program and
brother James is going to read that in
closing. Right, brother?
>> Yes, indeed.
>> All right. So, stay tuned for that also.
All right. We hope that that answered
your question there as we continue to
move on.
>> Moving on. Stephen Goo asked, "Are there
any scriptures on how we are to treat
animals?"
>> All right, brother Dre. Is there some
scriptures on how we're supposed to
treat animals?
>> Absolutely. Let's go to uh Proverbs 12.
>> We going to read one verse there.
Proverbs 12 and we going to read verse
10.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Proverbs 12 and 10. When you get it,
James, go ahead.
>> A righteous man regardeth the life of
his beast.
>> Yep. But the tender mercies of the
wicked are cruel.
>> Hey, so if you righteous, you going to
regard the life of your beast. Now,
let's go over to 1 Corinthians 9 and
we're going to read verses 9 and 10
there.
>> When you get it, go ahead, brother. 1
Corinthians 9:es 9 and 10 say for it is
written in the law of Moses thou shalt
not muzzle the mouth of the ox that
treadth out the corn doeth God take care
for oxen
>> yes he does
go ahead
>> or saith he it all together for our
sakes for our sakes no doubt this is
written that he that plowth should plow
in hope, and he that threshest in hope
should be partaker of his hope.
>> That's right. So, if you laboring, you
should be able to get the fruit of your
labor as well. So, yes, we should have
some regard for uh animals that we have.
That's all I
>> Yeah, that's right, brother D. Shoot.
Even on the books, they got a lot of
laws that are there to protect animals.
>> Yeah. You know that that scripture that
says when the woman came to Jesus and
and asked for help and she said he says
not meat to take the children's bread
and give it to dogs. It say even the
dogs eat from the crumbs that fall from
the master's table. Where's the master's
table at that the dogs eating the crumbs
from?
Right there in the house.
>> Yep. Yep. All right. Good point on that,
brother. And we hope that answered their
question as we move on.
>> Moving on. Jay Flo asks, "Was Jesus
actually nailed to a cross?"
>> All right. Was Jesus actually nailed to
a cross? Brother Julius,
>> let's look at his testimony. He told you
in Isaiah 34:16, "Seek ye out of the
book of the Lord and read. None of it
shall fail." Let's go to Psalm 22.
spend a little time with this Cornell
quickly. Psalm 22 James
>> was Jesus actually nailed to a cross.
That is if you believe this book which I
do with everything within me. Psalm 22,
read verse one. Go ahead and read it.
>> My God, my God, why hast thou forsaken
me? Why art thou so far from helping me
and from the words of my roaring?
>> David wrote about the Lord's experience
of the betrayal and the crucifixion.
David wrote about what Jesus would say
on the cross because he he is written
the spirit of the Lord spake by me. Give
me verse 16. Go ahead.
>> For dogs have compassed me. The assembly
of the wicked have enclosed me.
>> Yes,
>> they pierced my hands and my feet.
>> This is not talking about David. This is
talking about Jesus. The Romans pierced
his hands and his feet. But what did
they put him on? Let's go to St. John
the 19th chapter.
The Bible said, "Prove all things."
So that anybody that's asking this
question, you don't have to doubt no
more. Now it belong. It's up to do you
believe it? We reading it.
St. John 19 and pick it up at verse 16
and 17. Go ahead.
>> Then delivered he him therefore unto him
unto them to be crucified. And they took
Jesus and led him away.
>> Go ahead.
>> And he bearing his cross.
>> Was Jesus actually nailed to a cross?
What do the book say? He bearing his
what?
>> His cross.
>> So he got that cross and he's being
going to be crucified to do what?
>> Went forth into a place called the place
of a skull, which is called in the
Hebrew Goltha.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Where they crucified him. That is the
way the Romans executed people through
crucifixion.
>> They would break your legs, but they
didn't break Jesus' legs to fulfill
prophecy where they crucified him. Yes.
>> And two other with him on either side.
One
>> that's the two thieves and Jesus in the
middle, sisters and brothers, where they
crucified this. Now, when they crucified
Jesus, Thomas was not there.
Thomas wasn't there. Now go over and
read uh
go over to uh verse
one of the uh 34. Verse 34.
Pick it up at 32 and then we'll uh 32.
Go ahead.
Then came the soldiers and break the
legs of the first and of the other which
was crucified with him.
>> Now the verse 34. What did the soldiers
do? Go ahead.
>> But one of the soldiers with the spear
pierced his side and forth came forth
with came there out blood and water.
>> Now I want you to underline pierced his
side. I want you to underline they
pierced my hands and my feet. And what
did John say? John bear record at 35. Go
ahead.
>> And he he that saw it bear record, and
his record is true, and he knoweth that
he saith true, that ye might believe.
>> So that you going to be asking these
kind of questions so that you can
believe. One more place, John the 20th
chapter, and we going to read 24. Start
at verse 24.
because Thomas was not there when Jesus
appeared to the disciples the first
time. But now go ahead and read that
verse 24. John 20 and 24. Go ahead.
>> But Thomas, one of the 12 called Ditimus
was not with them when Jesus came.
>> He wasn't with them. So now
what did John what did Thomas say? Pay
attention. Go ahead.
The other disciples therefore said unto
him, "We have seen the Lord."
>> Yes.
>> But he said unto them, "Except I shall
see in his hands the
>> my hands except I see his hands." And
what?
>> The print of the nails.
>> Yeah.
>> And put my finger into the print of the
nails and thrust my hand into his side,
I will not believe. Now, 8 days later,
Thomas came. Well, keep reading. Read on
into it. Go ahead.
>> And after 8 days, again, his disciples
were within. And Thomas with them. Then
came Jesus, the doors being shut, and
stood in the midst, and said, "Peace be
unto you."
>> Go ahead, brother. Then said he to
Thomas, "Reach hither thy finger, and
behold my hand, and reach hither thy
hand, and thrust it into my side,
>> and be not faithless, but believing."
>> Go ahead.
>> And Thomas answered and said unto him,
"My Lord and my God."
>> This last verse is for all of us that we
might believe. Go ahead.
Jesus saith unto him, Thomas, because
thou hast seen me, thou hast believed,
"Blessed are they that have not seen,
and yet have believed."
>> And that's where I stand. I wasn't
there. You weren't there. It is written.
And so I believe it. Yes. Jesus was
there to the cross. That's all I got.
Cornell.
>> Yes, sir. also known as it was made out
of a tree which is wood. Right, brother?
>> In the shape of a cross.
>> Yep. All right. We hope that answered
your question as we move on.
>> Moving on. At Masala asks, "What was the
exact mark of Cain and was it passed
down to his descendants?"
>> The exact mark of Cain. Let's go Genesis
4 where it talks about chain here.
Genesis 4.
And when you get there, brother,
cuz he slayed his little brother.
Started off bad way back then. All
right. Genesis 4 and pick it up at verse
eight.
>> And Cain talked with Abel his brother.
And it came to pass when they were in
the field that Cain rose up against Abel
his brother and slew him.
>> Go ahead.
>> And the Lord said unto Cain, "Where is
Abel thy brother?" And he said, "I know
not. Am I brother's keeper?"
>> Mhm.
>> And he said, "What hast thou done? The
voice of thy brother's blood prith unto
me from the ground.
>> And what was one of the things the Lord
said about Cain right here in 11? Go
ahead.
>> And now art thou cursed from the earth,
which hath opened her mouth to receive
thy brother's blood from thine hand.
>> Skip down to 14 and let's deal a little
bit with this Mark here. Go ahead.
Behold, thou has driven me out this day
from the face of the earth, and from thy
face shall I be hid, and I shall be a
fugitive and a vagabond in the earth,
and it shall come to pass that everyone
that findeth me shall slay me.
>> All right, go ahead. What the Lord say
here about this mark, which can be his
word as well. Go ahead. And the Lord
said unto him, "Therefore, whosoever
slayeth Cain, vengeance shall be taken
on him sevenfold."
And the Lord set a mark upon Cain, least
any finding him should kill him. And the
Lord set a mark upon Cain, lest any
finding him should kill him. So, looks
like nobody was going to kill Cain. Lord
set a mark upon Cain. But um that's all
I got and all I can read from that.
Anybody else?
>> Book don't say
>> answer to that question is don't nobody
know.
>> Right. So we're going to leave it right
there as we're going to move on to our
next question.
>> Next question yourself says why is Mark
27 verse9 attributed to Jeremiah?
Where was it? prayer as it was to
Zechariah 11 12 and 13. If someone could
expound on Zechariah 11
12 and 13, how it relates to Mark 27
verse9.
>> All right, brother Jerome, we know there
is no Mark 27, but shed some light from
there, brother.
Yeah, like Cornell said that there
actually no Mark 27. Uh it don't go all
the way to 27 actually.
But uh what you probably meant was
Matthews 27
verse 9. So let's read that. Matthews
27:9.
Okay, it says, "Then was fulfilled that
which was spoken by Jeremy the prophet,
saying, "And they took the 30 pieces of
silver, the price of him that was
valued, whom they of the children of
Israel did value."
Now when you when you read this Matthews
27-9,
you notice he said that Jeremy, which is
Jeremiah, it said he spoke. He spoke it.
It didn't say he wrote it.
>> Y
>> So when you go to Zachchariah,
Zachchariah actually wrote it.
Okay. So let's go to that Zechariah 11
and read verse 12 through13.
Okay, it says, "And I said unto them, if
ye think good, give me my price, and if
not, forbear."
So they weighed for my price 30 pieces
of silver.
And the Lord said unto me, cast it unto
the potter a goodly price that I was
prized at at of them. And I took the 30
pieces of silver and cast them to the
potter in the house of the Lord.
>> Yeah. So they they talking about the
same thing. The only difference is is
letting you know in that Matthews that
Jeremiah uh spoke it, but Zachchariah
actually wrote it. That's all I got on
you.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
As we move on to our next one,
>> our next one. Malikica Banks asks, "What
do I OG families manage?
How do again Malikica Banks asks, "How
do I OG families manage things like
sports and other extracurricular
activities for their children while
still keeping the Sabbath day?"
>> All right. When it comes to sports and
extracurricular activities, how do you
handle that and keep the Sabbath? Guess
Cara.
Well,
we uh uh really we don't get off into
telling people how to conduct their
family. What we do is we teach the Bible
and whatever the Bible tell you to do,
then that is what dictates to the family
what they supposed to do. So, we don't
have no set uh uh uh laws or statutes or
directive that tell people what to do,
what to tell the people what to do about
certain activities. We tell them to read
the book. We teach the law. We don't try
to enforce it. That's all I had to say.
>> All right, we'll leave it right there as
we move on to our next question.
>> Next one. Valencia wants you to explain
First Corinians 10 verse 29.
>> 1 Corinthians 10 and verse 29. Dre, what
you say?
Well, let's this is Paul talking about
things, but let's read verse 23 and
we're going to skip to 27 and read to
29. So, read that, brother James, when
you get it. Go ahead.
>> Okay. 1 Corinthians 10 and 23 says, "All
things are lawful for me, but all things
are not expedit
expedient." All things are lawful for
me, but all things edify not.
>> So he's saying that everything that that
is lawful for him don't edify others.
Now skip down to verse 27. Go ahead.
>> If any of them that believe not bid you
to a feast, and ye be disposed to go,
whatsoever is set before you, eat,
asking no question for conscience sake.
So he ain't telling you to eat unclean
things. He say if they bid you to a
feast, go.
If they if if anyone that believe not
bid you to a feast, go. And if you be
disposed to go, whatever is set before
you, eat asking not for conscience sake.
Go ahead. Mhm.
>> But if any man say unto you, this is
offered and sacrificed unto idols, eat
not this for his sake that showed it,
>> and for conscious sake, for the earth is
the Lord's and the fullness thereof.
>> Okay? So don't eat it for the conscious
sake of the person that's asking it. Now
verse 29 is what you ask about. Go
ahead. conscience, I say, not thine own,
but of the other. For why is my liberty
judged of another man's conscience?
>> Now, let's bag up and look at a a
similar incident with this same kind of
deal. Let's go back to 1 Corinthians 8.
1 Corinthians 8. And I want you to read
verse 10. 1 Corinthians 8 and 10. Go
ahead when you get it, brother. For if
any man see thee which hath knowledge,
sit at me in the idol's temple, shall
not the conscience of him which is weak
be emboldened to eat those things which
are offered to idols.
>> Yep.
>> Now they emboldened to eat them things
cuz they looking at you and you got
knowledge. Now skip down to verse 12 and
read 12 and 13. Go ahead, brother.
But when ye sin so against the brethren,
and wound their weak conscience, ye sin
against Christ.
>> Wherefore, if meat make my brother to
offend, I will eat no flesh while the
world standeth, least I make my brother
to offend.
>> So he said, I'm not going to offend my
brother by eating meat. But let me tell
you, show you something that the Lord
said about this kind of thing. Let's go
to Isaiah 66 and we going to read verses
15 to 17. When you get it, go ahead,
brother.
>> Okay. Isaiah 66 and verses 16 and 17.
>> Verses 15.
>> 15 and 16 through 17. Yes. Verse 15
says, "For behold, the Lord will come
with fire and with his chariots like a
whirlwind to render his anger with fury,
and his rebuke with flames of fire."
>> Mhm.
>> For by fire and by his sword will the
Lord plead with all flesh, and the slain
of the Lord shall be many.
>> So, this is talking about the coming of
the Lord. Who is he talking about? The
slain of the Lord being many. Go ahead.
>> They that sanctify themselves and purify
themselves in the gardens behind one
tree in the midst, eating swine's flesh,
and the abomination, and the mouse shall
be consumed together, saith the Lord.
>> So those things that the Lord call an
abomination,
we should not eat them.
>> Right?
So, this is not talking about eating
anything, but I pause with that.
>> Yes, sir. There's a dietary law that we
must keep, Brother Dre.
>> Yes, sir.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
As we move on to our next question,
>> next one. Liz says, "I'm reading the
chapter of Ruth. Can you give me
understanding of who she is?"
Who is Ruth?
Yes. Call him.
>> Ruth
come out of the lineage of Lot,
Abraham's
nephew.
That make
Ruth
a Hebrew.
That's all it is to say. She uh uh she
married a Hebrew Israelite
and he died and she end up marrying
another one and she is the one and she
end up being King David's grandmother.
But Ruth is a woman that said that look
told is her mother-in-law which is a
Hebrew Israelite. Your God is my God and
my people is my people. So she end up
married another Israelite
and out of the one that she marries the
lineage came King David.
So Abraham's
was a Hebrew that make Lot his nephew a
Hebrew
and she came out of Lot that makes her a
but she was not an Israelite.
That's all I have to say.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on with a time
check.
>> Yes, the time is 8:26.
Uh, next question. Is pleasing oneself a
sin.
>> Is it a sin? Yes, caller.
>> Go to First John 3 and4.
Read it.
1 John 3 and4 says, "Whosoever
committeth sin transgresseth also the
law, for sin is the transgression of the
law."
>> Now, so I can't call it a sin. Neither
can I call it not one. I don't know. Or
the book don't say.
Now, what was the other part of this
question?
>> That was it.
No,
>> something else I thought was here. Can
you explain what Leviticus 25 means?
>> That's not the That's the next a
separate question.
>> That's it with this question.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah, you you answered that question.
That's all it was is pleasing oneself
for sin. That's called that was all that
was to it.
>> Okay.
>> All right. We're going to move on to our
next question.
>> Next question. Marilyn says, "Can you
explain what Leviticus 25
uh no verses given means?"
>> All right. So, Marilyn, uh, no, we can't
explain Leviticus 25 because there's 55
verses inside of that book and we
wouldn't be able to spread our time
evenly amongst our viewers and they
question. So, if you have a couple of
scriptures in that Leviticus 25 that you
would like for us to shed some light on,
please resubmit your question, but
covering the whole chapter, we just
simply can't do that.
All right, Sister Deborah, are we going
into new territory?
>> Uh, yes, we are. We are now into
tonight's Q&A for Wednesday,
January the 21st, 2026.
Zion uh says in Matthew 24 verse 15 when
we see the abomination of desolation
where does it say make your way to the
east because in Matthew 24
26 it says do not go if they say he is
in the desert. sir.
>> All right. So, let's go to that Matthews
24,
>> verse 15,
>> and we'll pick it up at that verse 15,
then skip down to that 26. And when we
read those, Deborah, please um state
that question again. Pick it up at 15.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Matthew 24:15 says, "When ye
therefore shall see the abomination of
desolation spoken of by Daniel the
prophet stand in the holy place,
whosoever readeth, let him understand."
>> Run, read that 26.
>> Wherefore, if they shall say unto you,
Behold, he is in the desert, go not
forth. Behold, he is in the secret
chambers. Believe it not.
>> Question, Deborah.
>> Yes. The question he states or she
states in Matthew 24 verse 15, when you
see the abomination of desolation,
where does it say make your way to the
east? It didn't say that. He said also
because in Matthew 24 26 it says do not
go if they say he is in the desert. So
he want to know where does it say make
your way to the east.
>> Yeah I didn't see where it said that
either. But let's open that up to the
panel.
>> Well listen let's look at it. Let's go
and and read a little more. When you see
the abomination standing over the place,
let's go and see what is there and read
down. Let's see what it says.
>> So, verse pick it up at 16, brother.
>> Okay.
>> Then let them which be in Judea flee
into the mountains. Let him which is on
the housetop not come down to take
anything out of his house.
Neither let him which is in the field
return back to take his clothes.
And woe unto them that are with child,
and to them that give suck in those
days.
But pray ye that your flight be not in
the winter, neither on the Sabbath day.
For then shall be great tribulation,
such as was not since the beginning of
the world, to this time no, nor ever
shall be.
And except those days Uhhuh.
>> finish it.
>> And except those days be shortened,
there should no flesh be saved. But for
the elect's sake, those days shall be
shortened.
>> Now it tell you where to flee. It tells
you to flee. Now let's go in the 12th
chapter of Revelation and it tell you
where to flee to.
>> Yes, sir. I don't remember I don't
remember nobody saying that you go to
the east. I'm just saying the Lord said
flee. Now let's go and find out where he
said flee to. We going to Revelation the
12th chapter
and uh we're going to start at the top
at verse uh uh one. Let's see. And then
we going we going to skip down.
Let's see. 12.
read the one
and uh uh uh
1 and two.
>> Okay. Revelation 12 verse 1 and 2 says,
"And there appeared a great wonder in
heaven, a woman clothed with the sun and
the moon under her feet and upon her
head a crown of 12 stars.
And she being with child cried
travailing in birth and pain to be
delivered."
Now, Genesis the 30 uh uh uh the uh the
Genesis the uh I think it's the 27th
chapter will tell you that this woman is
talking about Israel.
And again too, it let you know that uh
uh uh she brought a f a manchild brought
forth for she were prevailing to have a
a pregnant you know she was pregnant
prevailing to have a child and let's see
who she brought forth. Skip down to
verse five.
>> And she brought forth a
>> And she brought forth a manchild who was
to rule all nations with a rod of iron.
And her child was caught up unto God and
to his throne.
>> Uh-huh. Now
>> that's Jesus.
>> Mhm. Yeah.
>> Now we down to the end time now cuz this
woman talking about Israel physically
mostly but spiritually too because
always been a mixed multitude. And what
did the woman do? Go ahead.
>> And the woman fled into the wilderness
where she had placed her had a place
prepared of God that they should feed
her there a,23
score days.
Now, so the Lord is going to prepare a
place called,
you know, uh uh going uh uh uh prepare a
place in the wilderness for his people
that when they see this abomination
stand in the holy place, they will they
will know where to flee to. Now, let's
skip down
uh uh cuz the Lord there was a a a war
in heaven and Satan got thrown out. So,
we going to get uh uh uh get down to the
meat of this about fleeing
>> verse 14.
>> Let's let's
>> Huh?
>> You want verse uh 13 or 14?
>> Let's start at 13.
>> Okay.
Verse 13 says, "And when the dragon saw
that he was cast unto the earth, he
persecuted the woman which brought forth
the manchild."
>> Uhhuh. And to the woman were given two
wings of a great eagle that she might
fly into the wilderness and to her place
where she is nourished for a time and
times and half a time from the face of
the serpent.
>> Now that's three and a half years.
That's during the time of the great
tribulation.
>> Yes.
>> So the Lord said flee there cuz the Lord
going to prepare a place there and
that's where you are going to be safe.
Now let's go in the 91st chapter of
Psalms.
Psalm 91. Let's see.
Pick it up around there. A thousand
shall fall at thy side
>> up higher.
>> 91 and verse one.
>> Yeah. Right.
>> Psalm 91 and verse one says, "He that
dwelleth in the secret place of the most
high shall abide under the shadow of the
almighty."
>> I will say of the Lord, "He is my refuge
and my fortress, my God. In him will I
trust.
>> Surely he shall deliver thee from the
snare of the fowler, and from the
noisome pestilence.
>> Go ahead.
>> He He shall cover thee with his
feathers, and under his wings shalt thou
trust. His truth shall be thy shield and
buckler.
>> Because the people, they say his truth
going to be your shield and buckler.
That mean that people that know the
truth when they see the abomination of
desolation go into the holy place, they
are going to know who that is. And so
they going to run. Go ahead.
Thou shalt not be afraid for the terror
by night, nor for the arrow that flieth
by day,
nor for the pestilence that walketh in
darkness, nor for the nor for the
destruction that wasteth at noonday.
>> Uhhuh.
>> A thousand shall fall at thy side, and
10,000 at thy right hand, but it shall
not come nigh thee. Go ahead.
>> Only with thine eyes shalt thou behold
and see the reward of the wicked.
Because thou has made the Lord, which is
my refuge, even the most high thy
habitation.
>> Uh-huh.
>> There shall no evil befall thee, neither
shall any plague come nigh thy dwelling.
For he shall give his angels charge over
thee, to keep thee in all thy ways.
So now this woman which talking about
his servant the spiritual Israel as well
as physical
they going to go into this place of
safety. This is the wilderness and the
angel is going to be there and protect
you like he did when he brought us out
of Egypt. He took us into the wilderness
the same wilderness that our forefathers
came through. Now once Jesus come, he
going to find us in the wilderness and
then he is going to return everybody,
every Israelite, no matter where he is
on this planet, he going to take him
back to the land. But before that, he
going to take him through the
wilderness, the place of safety. Let's
go into Ezekiel the 20th chapter and
look at this.
Ezekiel chapter 20
and we're going to start there uh uh at
uh 33 and we're going to read a little
bit.
>> Okay.
>> Ezekiel 20:33 says, "As I live, sayaeth
the Lord God, surely with a mighty hand
and with a stretched out arm and with
fury poured out will I rule over you."
Uh-huh.
>> And I will bring you out from the
people, and will gather you out of the
countries wherein ye are scattered, with
a mighty hand, and with a stretched out
arm, and with fury poured out,
>> and I will and I will bring you into the
wilderness of the people, and there will
I plead with you face to face.
>> Now, when Jesus come, he going to find
some people already in the wilderness.
They were a part of the people that we
read about in the 12th chapter of
Revelation. They will have fled there.
They've been waiting there under the in
the uh uh under the protection of the
Lord for three and a half years. So now
when Jesus come, he going to take us
back to the land. But before the land,
we going through the wilderness. So he
going he going to do what now? Take off
what you keep continually.
Verse 36 says, "Like as I pleaded with
your fathers in the wilderness of the
land of Egypt, so will I plead with you,
sayeth the Lord,
>> and I will and I will cause you to pass
under the rod, and I will bring you into
the bond of the covenant, and I will
purge out from among you the rebels, and
them that trans."
You got some of these people that's
kicking against the word of God, kicking
against the name of Jesus, kicking
against the baptism.
You are going to be purged in the
wilderness. Go ahead and read.
>> And them that transgress against me, I
will bring them forth out of the country
where they sour, and they shall not
enter into the land of Israel, and ye
shall know that I am the Lord.
So now
it don't say flee to the east. It says
flee. Then it tell you where to flee. We
just happen to know that that's
northwest uh uh uh uh Arabia and South
Arabia. Uh Saudi Arabia northwest. How
do I know? Because they took over the
land of Midian.
And that's where the Lord that's where
the wilderness was around that area.
Mount Si where he came down and gave the
ten commandments
is in the land of Midian. So Saudi
Arabia on it now. But the Lord is going
to check it out for us.
So now it tell you where to flee. Don't
say east. It tell you where to flee to
the wilderness. When you find out where
the old wilderness is, that's where we
going to go and God is going to prepare.
But now the second part of this he talk
he says about the uh what it says uh uh
if they say
uh uh he's in the wilderness uh uh in
the desert. What? Read that again.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. You want me to read the question
again?
>> Okay. Because in Matthew 24 26 it says
do not go if they say he is in the
desert.
Uh where else
>> where they shall
>> so verse so Matthew 24 and 26 says
wherefore if they shall say unto you
behold he is in the desert go not forth
behold he is in the secret chamber
chambers believe it not.
Now,
Jesus is telling you that because they
going to tell you that the Lord is back.
We going to go and show you what I'm
saying about that. We going to come back
here. Let's go into second Thessalonians
the 2 chapter and start reading at verse
one.
>> Second Thessalonians
>> 2 chapter verse one.
>> Verse one. So this going it's exactly
what the people going to say before the
Lord come. Go ahead cuz let you know
Paul let you that the Lord cannot come
until this happen. Go ahead. Now we
beseech you, brethren, by the coming of
our Lord Jesus Christ, and by our
gathering together unto him,
that ye be not soon shaken in mind, or
be troubled, neither by spirit, nor by
word, nor by letter, as from us, as that
the day of Christ is at hand.
Let no man deceive you by any means, for
that day shall not come except there
come a falling away first and that man
of sin be revealed the son of predition.
Now he's letting you know right now
people going to say well if Christ can
come this or Christ going can come or
either the time going to come when
somebody say he is in the uh uh uh in
the temple the secret place but he's
saying look Christ cannot come until
that man of sin be revealed don't let
nobody tell you that he's here certain
things got to happen and let's see about
this uh a man that son this man is going
to be revealed. What verse is that?
>> That was verse three we read sir.
>> Go ahead. Verse four. Who opposeth and
exaltth himself above all that is called
God or that is worshiped. So that he as
God siteth in the temple of God showing
himself that he is God.
Now see this is the one they going to be
saying you know he's in the desert or
even but then they going to say you know
Christ have return he is in the holy
place he is in the temple of God which
is the holy place and he going to
present himself as God because it said
that going to stand in the in the temple
of God showing himself to be God. Keep
reading.
Remember ye not, that when I was yet
with you, I told you these things.
And now, and now ye know what
withholdeth, that he might be revealed
in his time.
So now we know what's going to happen.
We know they got to build a temple in
Jerusalem. We know that the pope of Rome
is going to have to go into that temple
and they going to be saying Christ is
back because he's saying showing himself
as God. So he said, "When you hear that,
don't believe it." Now, I'm going to
show you how I'm going to come. Now,
let's go back to uh uh 24th chapter of
St. Matthews, and we're going to read
verse uh uh uh
>> 27
cuz he letting you know this is the way
I'm going to come. I ain't going to
sneak up on you. I ain't going to come
end up going they going to build that
temple and then all of a sudden the pope
going to move into it and then they
going to say, "Well, Christ is back. He
said, "I'm going to show you how I'm
coming back." Read verse 27, 24, and 27.
>> For as the lightning cometh out of the
east and shineth even into unto the
west, so shall also the coming of the
son of man be.
>> So he let you know,
I'm not going to sneak up on this earth
and then you hear that I'm already in
the temple. Just like you see the
lightning come in heaven, like when it's
lightning, everybody going to see it. He
says, "So shall the son of man coming of
the son of man be." And then he gonna
tell you what time he's going to come.
Skip down to verse 29 and continue.
Immediately after the tribulation of
those days shall the sun be darkened,
and the moon shall not give her light,
and the stars shall fall from heaven,
and the powers of the heavens shall be
shaken.
>> Go ahead. Yeah.
And then shall appear the sign of the
Son of Man in heaven. And then shall all
the tribes of the earth mourn, and they
shall see the Son of Man coming in the
clouds of heaven with power and great
glory.
>> So now he's telling you, don't let
nobody fool you saying I'm back and I'm
in the temple. I'm going to come just
like you see the lightning when it
light. And I'm gonna come after the
three and a half uh uh great
tribulations which going to be three and
a half years that this man is going to
bring on this earth all kind of courage
and destruction. And after that then you
going to see me and you going to know
I'm coming. Not only am I going to come
like a lightning shine from the heaven,
the sun going to go black, the moon
going to turn red, and the stars are
going to
fall. And on your own time, you can go
into the sixth chapter of Revelation and
tell you in the heavens going to roll
back like a scroll. All that's got to
happen before Jesus come. Cuz somebody
say he's in the desert or he's in the
temple of God that they going to build
in Jerusalem. You say,
"Uh-uh."
But when Jesus come, just like we just
read here, every eye going to see him.
That's all I have to say about both of
them.
>> All right. Thank you for that. As we
move on to our next question with a time
check.
>> Yes, the time is 8:49.
Miss Way asks in John 20 verse 23.
Jesus gave the apostles power to retain
or retain sin. Do the priests of Israel
have that same power today?
John 20
verse 23.
Read that, brother. And that you would
like to know whether or not the priests
of today still have that same power. And
we're going to open it up to the panel.
Right ahead, brother.
>> You said John 20 23. Correct.
>> Correct.
>> Okay. Whosoever sin ye remit, they are
remitted unto them. And whosoever sin
you retain, they are retained.
>> They are retained.
>> So open to the panel. Is that power
still available today?
Well, the first thing is priest can't
get uh uh uh can't uh uh uh cast out
somebody else's sin.
And neither
and neither
can uh uh the priest uh uh
make somebody sin.
What do those two words mean? What does
remit mean? Somebody tell me.
>> Uh to release.
>> Huh? and re to release and then retain
is to hold.
>> Right? Priest can't do none of that.
Never could. Even Jesus didn't do that.
Nope.
>> Each individual have to work out their
own salvation.
And everybody's responsible for his own
sin. Let's go into Ezekiel the 18th
chapter
and we're going to start uh uh uh uh
we're going to start at verse one.
Ezekiel 18 and uh uh
verse one. When you get there, read it.
>> Okay. Ezekiel 18:11 says, "The word of
the Lord came unto me again, saying,
What mean ye that ye use this proverb
concerning the land of Israel, saying,
The fathers have eaten sour grapes, and
the children's teeth are set on edge."
As I liveth, as I liveth, sayeth the
Lord God, ye shall not have occasion
anymore to use this proverb in Israel.
Behold, all souls are mine. As the soul
of the father, so also the soul of the
son is mine. The soul that sinnth, it
shall die.
>> Skip now to verse 20 and read that.
Verse 20 says, "The soul that sinnth, it
shall die. The son shall not bear the
iniquity of the father, neither shall
the father bear the iniquity of the son.
The righteousness of the righteous shall
be upon him, and the wickedness of the
wicked shall be upon him."
So everybody's responsible for his own
sin. All the priests could do is teach
the people what sin is
and the consequences of it. And that's
all the priest could ever do. That's all
I have to say.
>> Yep. From that point, you got to work
out your own salvation with fear and
trembling. That's it.
>> Yeah. All right. I hope that answered
your question there as we move on to our
next one with time a ticket.
Yes. Toriia Mullen says, "I wanted to
know, is it okay to work out while
fasting?"
>> Is it okay to work out while you are
fasting?
>> Yeah, I didn't see where you couldn't,
but you know, just keep an eye on your
strength.
>> Ain't no
scripture written pro or con about that,
right?
>> We don't know. Yeah. All right, we're
gonna move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Brit Brat asks,
"Are people who are superstitious
considered idolizers?"
Um,
yeah. I mean, they got a lot of them out
there that don't pertain to life itself.
You know, step on a crack, break your
mother's back, and walking under a
ladder. If it don't fold on you, you'll
be okay. Splitting a pole. There so many
so many we could name
>> that they have come up with
>> cross in front of you. I don't know what
that
>> answer. Yep. So,
yep. So be aware of that as we continue
to move on to our next question.
>> Next one. Shenquila
uh Au Joby asks,
"Jesus
was sent to lead by example and take
away animal sacrifice since he became
the sacrifice for us. Are we meant to
build a relationship with him
specifically or with the father?
>> Will somebody go read what Jesus said?
If you love me, do what?
>> Keep my commandments.
John 15.
>> Read it.
>> John 15. And pick it up, brother. Verse
15.
>> Okay. John 15 and 15 says, "Henceforth I
call you not servants, for the
servants,"
>> John 14 and 15. 14 and 15. My apology,
brother,
>> not a problem. John 14 and 15 says, "If
ye love me, keep my commandments."
>> And that and that is what it's all
about. Now go and ask find out what a
young man asked Jesus what should he do
to get eternal life.
>> Yes.
In Matthew 19.
>> Yep.
>> Right. In search mode you say Matthew 19
>> and 16.
>> Okay. It Yeah. Matthew 19:16 says, "And
behold, one came and said unto him, good
master, what good thing shall I do that
I might may have eternal life?" And he
saith unto him, "Why callst thou me
good? There is none good but one, that
is God. But if thou will enter into
life, eat the commandments."
Now,
it's got nothing to do with your What?
What do you say? Personal. Read that
again, Deborah.
>> Yes. Uh, he states, "Are we meant to
build a relationship with him
specifically
or with the father?"
>> Listen, you're [clears throat] supposed
to keep your commandments
and that is the relationship with him
and the father.
>> That is right.
Jesus said he knew only what his father
say.
>> Yeah.
>> Father
he told you in Ecclesiastes 12 and 13
fear God and keep his commandments. This
is the whole duty of man.
>> All that simple. So now who where did
the commandments come from? That come
from the father and the son. The only
reason we use a protocol is because now
Jesus is the high priest.
>> Yes.
>> So now you pray to the father, but you
have to do it in the name of
Jesus because he's the high priest.
>> So he is the one that's going to plead
your cause. I think let's go to first
John. I think the I think it's in the
second chapter where he said uh uh we
have an advocate
>> Jesus Christ the righteous.
>> Huh? Right.
>> Yes. That's uh 1 John chapter 2 verse
one.
>> God in verse one. Yeah.
>> It says, "My little children, these
things write unto you that ye sin not.
And if any man sin, we have an advocate
with the father, Jesus Christ, the
righteous.
>> So now he is the advocate because the
advocate is the high priest.
>> He [clears throat] take you
>> you pray to the father, but you got to
go in Jesus' name. It's in Psalms, I
can't remember exactly where it is now,
where he's saying, "Look to those that
serve other God, he ain't going to take
your name up in his in his lips."
>> Right. Yeah. So if the high priest don't
present you before God, you don't get
there. It's just like when you had the
animal sacrifice,
you couldn't go and kill your own animal
and go in there and shake the blood
before the veil of the temple. You had
to get the ordained priest to do that.
>> So you got to deal with both of them.
You pray to the father, but you do it in
Jesus' name.
>> James, read that two and three.
And hereby we do know that we know him.
If
>> read that, read that two and three.
>> Oh, two and three. Okay. Verse two says,
"For he is the propitiation
for our sins and not for ours only, but
also for the sins of the whole world."
>> So much for that personal relationship.
You're not the only one he has to deal
with. It's everybody. Go ahead. Mhm. For
and hereby we do know that we know him
if we keep his commandments.
>> That's how you have a relationship with
God and the father.
>> We just got and we keep going back,
didn't it? Jesus said, "If you love me,
keep my commandments." But who's the
commandments are there? The fathers,
too.
>> That's right.
>> Yeah.
>> Do you want a relationship with both of
them in order? You pray to the father,
but you do it in Jesus name.
Yeah,
>> like you said earlier, that that family
with more than one member. Right now,
it's two.
>> That's correct.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question, Sister Deborah. Let's take one
more before we bring our program to a
close.
>> Yes. Ever been asked, is there an age
the red heer should be when sacrificed?
panel. Is there a age that the red heer
should be
under sacrifice?
>> Any clue?
>> Ain't no such thing as the red heer no
more. You got the over there
using that. That was done away with it.
Didn't no age then. But you don't do
that no more. Since Jesus died, that is
done.
>> Yeah.
>> So you got a bunch of uninformed people
which is still strangers. Edom that call
themselves Jews dealing with something
that was terminated when Jesus died on
the cross.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And that's all we have to say.
>> All right, Sister Deborah. Time check.
>> 9:01.
>> 9:01. So, we have ran out of time and we
want to thank everybody from all around
the world who tuned in with us and sent
in those questions. We thank you and we
say if you submitted a question, we
didn't get to it, please don't resubmit.
Sister Deborah, take it, put it in
rotation, and we will deal with that
question next week. But until we all
come together again, we ask that you
please be safe,
>> be blessed, stay prayed up, and stay
warm during these next days of cold. As
brother James closes us out,
>> our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven. Give us this day our daily
bread, and forgive us our debts as we
forgive our debtors, and lead us not
into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom and the
power and the glory forever. In Jesus
name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen.